ARLETTE MCDUFFIE Full Stack Web/Multimedia Developer & Graphic Artist mcduarle@aol.com

Relevant Qualifications and Specialties

I am a senior level Multimedia Engineer, Graphic Artist, Web Developer, and Full Stack Developer with over 18 years of experience in the areas of interest, capable of working independently and leading engineers less experienced. I've worked within the Intelligence community for the majority of my career and understand the unique challenges. With my proven track record of experience and interpersonal skills, I would be an exceptional addition to any team. My experiences range from Web Development/Interactive Media Development, Graphic Arts, conventional printing, and electronic publication; using the latest software applications, to create functional and efficient web sites, online interactive training material, brochures, poster, and other forms of visual communication. I've developed a web presence for a number of organizations within the Intelligence Community. I provided interactive pages and web portal for customers at external facilities using programming languages that include JavaScript, HTML, and XHTML. My coding skills also include ActionScript 3.0, HTML 5, CSS 3, and Marco used in Excel. My website development skill include development other applications such as Joomla, and SharePoint. Each web portal gave customers access to a number of databases populated with mission critical information. I've created very basic programs using Visual Studio. My experiences also includes working within a secured environment, providing timely and efficient services to customers, meeting customers, and presenting information in an effort to educate customers on existing services and/or projects.

Education

- A.A., Multimedia/Web Development, Art Institute of Washington, 2005
- B.A., Printing Management/Printing Production, Florida A&M University, 1995
- A.A., Graphic Arts, Miami Dade Community College, 1992

Employment History and Experience

General Dynamics Information Technology, Jan. 2012 – Present, Principal Specialist Multimedia

(Currently holding the same position with the same job tasking and previous job with BAE IT Systems)

As a Multimedia Developer for the Training group, I was responsible for creating online computer base training material. I integrate video and sound to make each training simulation more robust and effective to ensure greater retention of the information presented. Working closely with trainers and quality managers, I create online CBTs for large classroom setting and small one-on-one interaction. Each CBT was created to train mid to senior level management, domestically and abroad. I am also responsible for creating visually appealing materials used to display and showcase upcoming events, community activities, new desktop applications, and new training methods. I created posters, door signs, postcards, fliers, logos and web site designs.

Other job responsibilities range from coding macros inside of Excel spreadsheets, creating PowerPoint presentation, and developing websites in Joomla and SharePoint.

ARLETTE MCDUFFIE Full Stack Web/Multimedia Developer & Graphic Artist mcduarle@aol.com

BAE Systems, Jun. 2010 - Dec. 2011, Senior Multimedia Developer

As a Multimedia Developer for the Training group, I was responsible for creating online computer base training material. I integrate video and sound to make each training simulation more robust and effective to ensure greater retention of the information presented. Working closely with trainers and quality managers, I create online CBTs for large classroom setting and small one-on-one interaction. Each CBT was created to train mid to senior level management, domestically and abroad. I am also responsible for creating visually appealing materials used to display and showcase upcoming events, community activities, new desktop applications, and new training methods. I created posters, door signs, postcards, fliers, logos and web site designs.

Cerebral Solutions Inc. Sep. 2009 – Dec. 2009, Senior Multimedia Developer

As a Multimedia Developer for the for my client, I was responsible for creating visually appealing material to display and showcase upcoming events and community activities. I created posters, door signs, business cards, logos and web site designs. I played a key role in creating publications for distinguished universities and senior leader within the IT community. Many of the publication that I helped design and publish are now part of the IT community publication archives.

BAE Systems, 2003 - 2009 Senior Lead Web Developer

As the Financial Group website developer and manager, I provided an online portal of my customer onsite, in external facilities, and out in the field, worked closely with other team members to make financial databases and database tools and other pertinent information accessible. I work on web-based applications, website enhancements, desktop applications, database-backed websites and web layout enhancements; code web pages utilizing HTML, CSS, and other script/programming languages; design, code, and testing of technical solutions; creates and executes project work plans and revises as appropriate to meet changing needs and requirements; communicates and enforces coding standards; delivers informative, well-organized presentations; suggest areas for improvement in the internal processes along with possible solutions.

As the Ground Photography website developer and manager, I provided an online portal of our customer in external facilities and out in the field, worked closely with other team members to disseminate images to analyst within the Industry. I maintain a number of advertisement accounts creating visually inspiring flyers and other advertisement materials. My duties also include being an active member of the Library Marketing Committee, coordination and planning promotional events. I provided research service to photography analysts, assisting them in locating photos in the Ground Photography database or other existing databases. I am also responsible for cataloging metadata for photos collected by the Ground Photography staff analysts.

ARLETTE MCDUFFIE Full Stack Web/Multimedia Developer & Graphic Artist mcduarle@aol.com

Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC), 2000 – 2003, Web Master/Application Developer/Graphic Artist

I developed and maintained web sites for the clients making sure information was classified properly and posted to six different web sites under different classification levels. The web sites include various secure platforms, and a public Internet site. Each required different software and application usage, utilizing the latest technology for web development. I helped to develop a Microsoft Access Database. It contained elements of pertinent information describing the relationship between multiple organizations.

I maintained over 32 websites (creating and updating), on private and public domain. I implemented new and current web application and trends to meet customer's need and recommendations. I worked one on one with my clients and other tech groups to collaborate best practice to developing innovative applications.

CIA Printing and Photography Group, 1995 – 2000, Electronic Publication Specialist/Web Developer

At the Electronic Publication Center, I contributed to the development of a new working system for HTML productivity and job tracking of over 300 publications in hard copy and electronic format. I played a key role in developing the World Facts Book web site and publication.

Additional Technical and Specialty Training

Certifications: N/A

Other Courses: Structured Query Language I and II, Franklin Coveys 7 Habits of Highly Effective People, XHTML w/ CSS 1, 2, & 3, ActionScript

Computer Skills

Hardware: Hewlett-Packard, IBM PCs and compatibles, Macintosh, Scanners/OCRs, Sun Workstations

Software/Programming Languages: Macromedia Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Flash, PageMill, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe ImageReady, Adobe InDesign, QuarkXpress, Corel Draw, Finial Cut Pro, SoundEffectd, Soundtracks, FrameMaker, Lotus 1-2-3, MS Excel, MS Word, MS Power Point, MS Access, Acrobat, Netscape, Explorer, Microsoft Outlook, PageMaker, PowerPoint, VISIO, Virus Scan, WordPerfect, HTML, SGML, XHTML, CSS (1, 2, 3), ActionScript, JavaScript, Visual Basic, Microsoft Visual Studio, MediaWiki, TracWiki, Joomla, WordPress, Node.js

Databases: SQL Server

Operating Systems: Mac OS, Solaris, SunOS, UNIX, Windows, Windows 95, Windows for Workgroups, Windows NT

Networking/Communications: N/A

Achievements

Honors: Class Project: "Harlem Renaissance" Featured web site in The Art Institute of Washington 2006/2007 Catalog

Awards: N/A
Publications: N/A

Clearances

TS/SCI w/Poly